# Camino Losada Alonso

## Full-Stack Developer

Specialized in the **MERN stack** (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js), highly focused on **best practices**, **clean code**, and **Agile ecosystems**. I never miss the opportunity to explore and use technologies and tools that prioritize achieving an **optimal user experience** above all. And how did I get here? After completing my biology degree and specializing in fish and aquariums, I joined a **startup**, an environment in which I grew immensely both personally and professionally, **reaching goals far from my comfort zone**. All of this fueled my desire to take on what has been my **greatest and most satisfying challenge**: **programming**.

## Experience

### **Full-Stack Web Development**

05/2023 - Present

Freelance - DeveloPez

Development of web applications in **Agile** environments, adopting a **Sprint**-based approach to ensure **efficient** and **high-quality** delivery: participation in **planning**, **review**, and continuous improvement **retrospectives**.

Rigorous **version control** and **CI/CD** workflow management, overseeing all code through **workflows**, unit **testing**, and integration testing to ensure **clean** and **sustainable code**. Monitoring key aspects such as **accessibility**, **good practices**, **SEO**, and **performance**.

- ~ LINKLIST app
- ~ TICKET-IN app
- ~ BRETARO app

#### **Aauarist**

**Aquarium Barcelona & Aquadec Aquariums** 

11/2021 - 04/2023

Experience in the care and **well-being** of aquatic life, attending to each and every **detail** that makes it possible. Projects **coordination**.

#### **Aguaponics operations & Communication**

Green in Blue (before Aquapioneers)

12/2018 - 11/2021

Acomplishments:

#### ~Brand Identity and Community Building

Creation of the **brand identity** and product from scratch, enabling Green in Blue to establish a strong **presence on social media**. This effort has allowed the company to build a prominent aquaponics **community** in Catalonia and Spain, gaining remarkable international recognition within the **sustainability** ecosystem.

#### ~Education and outreach about aquaponics

Creation of theoretical-practical educational materials and the delivery of **courses** and **workshops**.

~Biotechnology and Production

**Strategic planning** and involvement in the design of facilities, selection of cultivated products, and their ultimate destination.

#### Education

#### **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT Program**

ISDI CODER

01/2023 - 05/2023

Approximately 1000 hours dedicated to practical programming in a **collaborative Agile environment**, subject to demanding **deadlines**.

### Bachelor's Degree in Biology & MSc in Aquaculture

Universidad Santiago de Compostela



Barcelona

635014101

🔀 camino.losada.alonso@gmail.com

in in/caminolosadadeveloper

github.com/caminolosada

### Skills

#### ~FRONT-END & BACK-END

JavaScript · TypeScript · HTML5 CSS/SAAS · BEM · Styled-Components · React · Redux Vite · Axios · Netlify APIRest · Angular

Express.js · Node.js · MongoDB Mongoose · Postman · JWT · Joi validation · Render

#### ~TESTING

React Testing Library · Jest Vitest · Supertest · TDD Mock-Service-Worker · MongoDB-Memory-Server

# ~BEST PRACTICES & CLEAN CODE

Git · GitHub & Actions · CI/CD NPM · ESLint · Prettier Debugging · SonarCloud · Figma DevTools · Lighthouse · Trello Agile

#### ~LANGUAGES

Spanish · Galician Native

English · French · Catalan Working Proficiency

#### ~EMOTIONAL SKILLS

Empathy · Meticulousness Perseverance · Resilience Responsibility · Autonomy

## Recognition

Finalist in the **Jump2Digital Hackathon**, November 2023 (+100 participants)